[♪♪♪]
[BENNY MARDONES'
"INTO THE NIGHT"
PLAYlNG OVER SPEAKERS]
Hey, Captain America.
What's up, brother?
Hey, bro.
This is stupid.
WALT: You got a better idea?
Okay, fun. Whatever.
So when do we, you know?
We don't, for now.
No cooking until things settle down.
Settle down? I thought you' re the one
that said nothing's changed.
Look, l just put my family
through an ordeal
that they're just now
starting to accept, okay?
I can't--
Uh. That's too expensive.
Look, l can't leave my house
for more than 20 minutes
without my wife worrying.
I need time to mend fences.
Okay, so while
you' re fixing fences,
what about me, huh?
Your A-hole brother-in-law
took all my money.
That's $600.
Okay, what about the rest?
Rest of what?
Half your money's mine.
Fifty-fifty partners.
That's our business motto.
Meaning what, exactly?
That I suffer for your carelessness?
You' re the one who wanted
to work with Tuco.
Okay. lf it weren't for that,
none of this would've happened.
Just be cool.
We' ll talk about this
later, okay?
As for now, no contact.
Understood?
Whoa, whoa.
Where are you going?
I leave first.
Walt!
WALT: ln the kitchen.
Hey.
Hey. I didn't know
you were allowed to touch the stove.
Hilarious, Groucho.
Go on, grab a seat.
Juice is on the table.
What?
SKYLER: Good morning, honey.
WALT JR.: Hey, Mom.
Dad's cooking breakfast.
But don' t worry.
I'm also doing all the dishes.
Huh? Huh? Eh?
Nice? Follow me.
There's also orange juice
and grapefruit juice,
which, personally, as you know,
I've never been a fan of.
But considering all the polyphenols
and the limonoids, can't hurt.
Walt, you didn't have to do this.
I wanted to.
Grapefruit juice?
Yes, please. Thanks.
There you go. Honey?
No, I'll stick with orange, thank you.
All right. Dig in, dig in.
Pancakes are not getting hotter.
Wow.
Yeah.
There you go.
WALT:
All right. Got one. Steely Dan.
No.
Yes, absolutely.
No, in terms of
pure musicianship,
I would put them up against
any current band you can name.
You wouldn't know
any current bands.
[CAR HORN HONKING]
That's besides the point.
Have a good day, honey.
You too.
Ah! Boz Scaggs. There's another one.
Ugh! Boz Scaggs.
Whoever they are.
Bye. Thanks for breakfast.
Bye.
You' re welcome.
Listen, tell Louis
to drive carefully.
All right.
Our son doesn't know
who Boz Scaggs is.
We have failed as parents.
Come to think of it,
I barely know who Boz Scaggs is.
Stop it.
Give me your plate.
No, no. I'll get it. I'll get it. Yeah.
Thank you.
Mm-hm.
Hey, uh, listen,
in the calendar section
all week long
there's a fiction writer's seminar
at UNM.
And, you know,
probably talking about
how to get published
and that sort of thing.
Yeah?
Mm-hm.
Yeah, so, anyway,
I thought maybe you might...
I mean, I'll go with you if you like.
Oh, and, uh,
you know, I was thinking about
what you asked me the other night.
You know, you were wondering
if l had a second cell phone.
And, well, I've been
thinking about that a lot,
and l think what you heard
was my cell phone alarm going off.
I've been using it a lot
as a medication reminder
to, well, remind me
to take my medication.
And, well,
the weird thing is that
the alarm sound
is almost exactly the same
as the regular phone ring
which is really a poor design,
if you ask me. But l think
that was probably it.
I tried to go in
and change it to a different sound
other than the phone ring, but...
They so overcomplicate
these things.
Anyway, it was probably
just as well that l lost it.
There's got to be a new one
on the market by now.
You know, if we do this thing
at UNM, maybe on the way home
we can stop by,
and l can get a new cell phone.
[DOOR SLAMS]
Skyler?
[ENGINE STARTS]
[LINE RINGlNG]
[BUZZING]
Ready?
Yo, for what, might help.
[SIGHS]
Not another intervention.
GARDINER:
Jesse Bruce Pinkman,
pursuant to Section 47-8-1 3
of the New Mexico
Real Property Code,
you are hereby
given notice to vacate
the premises listed
as 9809 Margo,
Albuquerque, 871 04.
Wait. What?
You' re kicking me
out of my own house?
It's your aunt Ginny's house.
And she gave it to me.
She never
gave it to you, Jesse.
GARDINER:
You were allowed
residentiary privileges.
Your parents have always
been the property owners.
Look, we talked about this,
okay? I'd sell the house,
we'd split it fifty-fifty.
That was the deal.
What the hell happened?
What happened is
you' re a speed manufacturer.
No, I'm not. What?
MRS. PINKMAN:
A DEA agent came
looking for you, Jesse.
He came to our front door.
Okay, because I've actually
been helping them,
which l could get into
a lot of trouble for telling you,
so you're welcome.
I saw your basement.
Oh, yeah.
I was worried, so l went
over there and I let myself in,
and l found your laboratory.
You guys have your own key?
Manufacture of a Schedule II
controlled substance
is a second degree felony.
Under federal asset seizure,
the government can take
the entire house.
It's not even there anymore.
I cleaned it all out.
Son, we can't stop you
from ruining your life,
but you will not drag us down
with you.
GARDINER:
Vacate the house in 72 hours.
Otherwise, your parents
have authorized me
to contact the authorities.
Is that clear?
Do you have
any questions for us?
Three days, Mr. Pinkman.
Come on.
[CAR DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES]
Hi.
Hey.
Hey, I fixed the garage door.
Great.
Yeah.
One track was bent.
That's why it was bouncing.
Okay.
Where were you today?
Out.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, everything's fine.
Hey, you know, for what
it' s worth, l was thinking about
going back to those meetings,
the cancer support group.
I think that that' s good.
Yeah.
Yeah, that's good.
You were right
on the money about that.
It's good to, you know,
talk about things.
I think that's great.
Yeah.
[WATER RUNNING]
MRS. PINKMAN:
Jesse.
Jesse. Hey, Jesse.
You don't answer your phone?
Yeah, no, l've just been
pretty busy.
How'd you--?
Oh, right,
you have that key.
Hey, listen. Um...
So l've been thinking
a lot about our conversation
we had the other day,
and l completely get why
Dad totally tweaked off on me
like that and...
It's not just your father, Jesse.
No, I know. I know. I know.
I'm just saying it was a really,
really big wake-up call for me,
which is why I wanted
to talk to you.
You know, I've been
thinking real seriously
about business school, actually.
You can do the whole thing
from your computer now...
No, Mom, Mom.
Hey, hey, this is good.
You know, we're talking,
starting a dialogue.
The time for talking
has passed, Jesse.
Hey. Hey.
What the hell, yo?
I thought it was just a wake-up call.
We are putting it in storage.
When you decide to grow up,
you can have it back.
Why don' t you grow up, Mom?
Ginny wanted me here.
All right? I was the one
who took care of her.
I took her to her appointments
and made her lunch every day.
I earned this.
You did not make
her lunch every day.
What did you do, huh?
She' s lying there dying,
and where the hell are you?
Don't start with me.
Now what?
You' ve decided to,
oh, I don't know, make
your eldest son homeless?
Wow! Great family, Mom.
Why are you like this? Why?
You have two sets of keys
and the padlock to the garage.
Leave them
on the kitchen counter
when you leave.
No, Mom, Mom, Mom.
Hey, where am l
supposed to go?
I don't know, sweetheart.
But please
turn your life around.
Yeah, this is gonna help
big time with that. Bitch!
Jeez.
[DOORBELL RlNGS]
Oh, hey, Mr. White.
Hey, well, that's the way.
Don't just sit out there honking.
Come in and say hello.
Hey, we've got omelets.
You want an omelet?
No, I'm good.
New Mexican Christmas style,
red and green chilies.
No. Thank you, though.
Flynn and me gotta get going.
Who's Flynn?
Flynn.
He's your, uh...
Flynn?
Yeah.
So?
So? Nothing.
You ready?
Like it.
Bye, Mr. White.
Okay.
Bye.
Flynn? You know about
this Flynn thing?
Mm-hm.
Okay. Flynn. Yeah.
As in what, Errol?
I don't know. lt's what he likes
to be called these days.
What's wrong with Walter Jr.?
Don't take it personally.
He wants his own identity.
You think he told Louis
about me?
About the blackout?
Louis is his friend, Walt,
and your disappearance
upset him.
Hey, I made omelets.
[PHONE RINGING]
I'm going out,
but thanks, though.
Where you going?
Can you
get the phone, please?
Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely.
White residence.
JESSE:
Yo, it' s me. Is this a good time?
What part of "no contact"
didn' t you understand?
I know, but there' s a problem.
I don't care. We agreed.
No amount of
pay-per-view channels is
gonna make any difference.
Honey, we' re happy
with our cable provider, right?
Yeah, we're happy.
Skyler? Sky?
Where are you going?
Can you at least tell me that?
Out.
[PHONE RINGING]
Ooh. Should
probably get that, Walt.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Skyler.
What?
Yo, I get I shouldn't call,
but I'm in a situation over here,
and l need my money.
I just gave you $600.
Yeah, and thanks,
Daddy Warbucks,
but that was
before my housing situation
went completely
testicular on me, okay?
You smoked the entire 600,
didn't you?
What? No.
Yes.
No.
Look, Jesse,
your problems are just that:
Your problems.
No contact. Do not call here ever.
When the moment is right, l will call--
Mr. White, you're not listening.
They' re kicking me out of my house.
[BOTH GRUNT]
[LINE RINGlNG]
[PHONE RINGS]
You son of a bitch.
Uh! Son of a bitch.
Hey, thank you. Thank you so much.
Thanks, man. Hey, guy!
You forgot something! Yeah!
You forgot your ice trays!
You' re gonna need the ice trays!
Hey, you forgot something here!
Take this!
[GUlTAR PLAYING]
[JESSE SINGlNG]
[MICROWAVE BEEPING]
Hold on, buddy.
Yo, we should get
Twaughthammer up and
running again, yo. I'm serious.
I know. That sounded tight.
Hey,
thanks again, P.
I made sure this stucknut
exterminator, you know,
put me on his speed dial.
Two nights tops.
No, you still staying
at your aunt's on Margo?
Yeah. l'm thinking of moving.
Nob Hill, probably.
Jess-a-matic.
Living the dream.
[CHUCKLlNG]
Okay, buddy. You're gonna
eat your carrots like
we talked about, right?
Too hot.
No, no, buddy.
Remember. Okay?
Come on, yes.
Listen, hey,
talk to me, man.
Are you still having
mad relations out there?
You can talk to me.
I won't hate a player.
I can't lie. It's pretty hectic
out there, female-wise.
[SIGHS]
Damn. l'm hating, man.
That's why we need
to get the Hammer
up and running, you know?
Get you out of the house.
How awesome would that be?
Come on. Look. What?
Hm?
I cut all the green parts
off like you--
Just eat them. Please?
We should do this. You know,
track down Cheevo and
Anthony and demo up.
Get back in the scene.
I'm sorry, man. Just hold on
one second, all right?
Okay, listen. How about
you take a bite of your sandwich,
and then you take--
[DOOR OPENS]
Mommy' s home.
Hi.
Hello.
Hey, honey, you remember
Jesse Pinkman?
His house is getting bug bombed.
I said he could crash a few nights.
Hey, Jesse.
Hey.
Paul, could you help me
in the bedroom with these?
Sure. Yeah.
[SIGHS]
Yeah, l used to
not like carrots, too.
SARA: Hey, Hen, I think
it' s someone's nap time.
Come on.
[CHUCKLES]
Man, dude, you're gonna kill me.
I totally spaced that the in-laws
are crashing this weekend.
You got
other people to call?
No, that's cool.
I got tons of people. Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yo, in-laws?
Sucks to be you, P.
Yeah. Yeah, I know, huh?
Here.
See you, man.
It's good to see you.
[THE BELLAMY BROTHERS'
"LET YOUR LOVE FLOW"
PLAYlNG OVER SPEAKERS]
Look, l'm asking to crash three,
maybe four nights, and--
Look, l already called Badger,
all right? l called everyone.
I need a solid here, bro.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, whatever.
All right. All right.
Hey, how about this?
What if it's just for tonight?
[GRUNTS]
Wait. No, you cannot
be serious.
You cannot be serious!
Hey.
Someone took your bike, man.
Not cool.
[GRUNTlNG]
[YELLING AND GRUNTING]
[LIQUlD SLOSHING]
[COUGHlNG]
Morning.
Oh, hey.
Where did--?
Where did Mom go?
Out.
Um, where's breakfast?
Hey.
Let's go do something.
Like what?
Something fun.
WALT:
All right, ready?
Let's put it in gear.
Is your foot on the--? Okay. Good.
Yeah. l got it.
Good.
Yes. Nice and smooth.
Good. Just like that.
Good. I like the hands
at 1 0 and 2. Very nice.
Okay, let's slow down here
to a stop in preparation
for a left-hand turn. Okay.
All right. You might want to
go easier on the brake.
Sorry about that.
That's okay.
That's all right.
You' re doing fine.
Much better than last time, huh?
Oh, yeah, Louis has been helping me.
Has he?
Good. Good. Okay.
Don't forget the turn indic-- Good.
I'll stop talking.
You know what you're doing.
And let' s make
that left-hand turn.
Nice and smooth. Very nice.
Right hand.
Good. Good. Okay.
Are you using both feet?
Yeah.
No. Wait. Wait. No, Walt.
You can't do that.
You can't use one foot
on each pedal.
Why not?
Because you can't. Stop, Walt. Okay.
Just stop, please. Right. All right.
Dad, this is way easier.
Come on. There's the easy way,
and then there's the right way, right?
So let's just try it again,
right foot only.
All right.
Okay?
Okay, just-- You don' t have to--
Okay. All right. That' s fine.
Just-- That's okay. That' s okay.
Just try it again.
Here we go.
Let's just, just try it again.
Okay.
Don't-- Just easy.
Okay, okay, good. Great.
That was better. See?
Right? Better? Right.
The gas, the brake,
the gas, the brake.
I can't do this.
My legs don't
work that way.
Your legs are fine.
You just have to stick with it.
Don't set limits for yourself, Walt.
You' re all right.
All right. We'll get this.
I promise. Now let's
just try again. All right?
All right.
Here we go. Here we go.
Okay, well, you don't need to,
you know, just take off.
But all right, here we go.
Slow it down just a little bit.
All right, we have a turn
coming up here, so prepare
to apply the brakes.
Prepare, Walt, for the brakes.
Brakes, the brakes.
I'm braking.
You' re using both feet again.
It's not stopping.
That's the gas. Use the brake.
The break. Brake, brake, brake!
Okay.
That's one way to stop.
I told you.
Flynn.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
Hands up, asshole!
Yo, yo, it's cool.
So help me, I will spread you.
No, please, no, all right?
It's me, okay? lt's Jesse.
All right? Look, this is my RV.
You towed it.
Your cousin Badger, remember?
What the hell you doing here?
You smell like shit.
It's a long story.
So l fixed up your felonious
rolling laboratory here,
750 for the repair.
Make it a grand,
counting the toilet plus
the 500 you already owe me,
and you're good to drive on
out of here to someplace
far away. Upwind.
Okay, um...
Here's the thing.
I can't pay you today.
But I can pay you this week,
all right?
Seventeen fifty? We'll make it 1 750,
for, like, you know, interest.
I thought your word was your bond.
It totally is.
Definitely. I just don' t
have the money at
this particular moment.
But I will, soon.
Here's my counteroffer.
I kick you out.
I take payment
from your inventory.
I know a guy that' ll pay
premium for this kind of crap.
All right. Two grand. Okay?
Two days, two grand.
That's totally fair.
Just don't take my cook stuff.
All right? That' s all l got left.
Please, all right? l really...
God, I really need a break here.
Okay?
Clovis, come on.
I don't know.
There's a bunch of stuff in there.
There's something called
methylamine. Me-- Meth...
However the hell you pronounce it.
Methylamine.
I don't know. l banged on it.
It sounds pretty full to me.
Holy shit. How much?
[ENGINE STARTS]
Hey! Hey!
[SHOWER RUNNING]
WALT:
Skyler.
Louis took Walt to school.
I was thinking maybe
this would be
a good time to talk.
I dreamt that l owned
an antique bicycle
repair shop.
In Ireland.
Weird.
Sounds weird.
I wanted to apologize
for everything.
My
desire for privacy.
My emotional
unavailability.
Having cancer
doesn't excuse all that.
I haven' t been
a good partner to you,
and for that,
I'm very sorry.
I love you.
And l love this family.
And l just
want to make sure that
we don't lose contact.
Thank you.
Okay.
I agree.
Is that it?
God.
God, how long are
you going to do this?
Do what?
This.
Not talking to me.
Going out all day
and refusing to tell me where.
You are obviously angry with me
about something,
so let's talk about it.
Oh, God.
I feel like you' re upset with me
because you think
that I'm up to something.
Like what?
I have no idea, Skyler.
What, that I'm having an affair?
Is that it? ls that what you think?
Is that why you asked me
about the...
Some other phone?
Because you think
that I'm being unfaithful?
I don't know.
Okay.
So ask me.
Why?
Would you even tell me?
Yes. l would.
Of course I would.
And no. l'm not.
I'm not having an affair, okay?
Now, what do I do
to prove that to you?
Swear an oath? Okay.
My right hand to God.
I'm not having an affair.
I heard you, Walt.
You' re not having an affair.
Congratulations.
No, you know what?
Congratulations to you, Skyler.
Great job.
What is this?
What do I have to do?
I'm trying to talk to you, and you--
Okay, so talk, Walt.
Shut up and say something
that isn't complete bullshit.
You want to know
what you have to do?
You have to tell me
what's really going on right now.
Today. No more excuses.
No more apologies.
No more of these--
These obvious,
desperate breakfasts.
You don't want to lose
contact with me, Walt?
Good.
Then tell me.
Now.
Tell you what?
Skyler.
What is it you want me
to tell you? l don' t know.
We' re not done here. Skyler.
Do you know what
I've done for this family?
What the--?
Yo, I'm really sorry, okay?
What is wrong with you?
Why are you blue? Jesus.
I'm sorry. Let's just say it starts
with my parents being greedy,
kleptomaniac douche bags.
Are you actually this stupid?
No, look.
I know this isn't a optimal--
To come to my house and park
on my street, driving this vehicle.
I mean, what the hell is wrong
with you? l'm really asking.
Nothing. I'm sorry. I just--
What if Skyler had seen you?
What then? What was
the plan then, genius, huh?
I don't know.
You don't know.
You know why you don' t know?
Because you don't think. That's why.
You don't think. You never
figured out how to think,
did you, Pinkman?
I said I was sorry. l just need
my half of the money, and I will go.
Your half?
There is no your half
of the money.
There is only my all of it.
Do you understand?
Why should I be penalized
because of your sloppiness?
Look, that is completely uncool,
all right?
We agreed, fifty-fifty partners.
Partners in what?
What exactly do you do here?
I've been meaning to ask,
because l'm the producer, right?
I cook. But from what I can tell,
you are just a drug addict.
You are a pathetic junkie,
too stupid to understand
and follow
simple rudimentary instructions.
Too stupid to re--
[GRUNTlNG]
Do it.
Try not to touch anything.
Want some breakfast?
[NANCY SINATRA'S "IT'S SUCH
A PRETTY WORLD TODAY"
PLAYlNG OVER SPEAKERS]
[♪♪♪]